Garrett Rose

Web Developer

903 South Main St. Clover, SC 29710 Squarrett.rose03@gmail.com \$803-526-3367

🦪 github.com/glrose 🖈 Website 💆 Marine Corps

MY JOURNEY

I have had a broad range of experience in technical environments. Electrical planning, tier 3 data center expertise, software, IT and excellent leadership skills. Most of my free time is spent learning software engineering and programming. Software engineering is something that I enjoy and strive to learn more about every day.

P SKILLS

HTML | Javascript (React, Node Js, Vue, Jquery, Express, Cheerio) | CSS (Styled-Components)

MongoDB | PHP | Wordpress | Bootstrap | Heroku | Git | Linux | C++ (C)

Python ((Entry Level)) | **Figma**

క్టా QUALIFICATIONS

- Strong ability to create web pages from scratch using HTML, CSS, and Javascript.
- Certified for NoSQL databases, and NodeJS development through MongoDB University.
- Repeated use of git version control to record and implement proper organization of branches for managing web content.
- Fundamentally developed team member and problem solver due to Marine Corps, and electrical industry experiences.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

API Software Query Developer, Freelance

I worked for a grocery management client that needed tooling for food item data. My task was to develop a UPC code search application from scratch that displays nutrition data on over 650k USDA food certified items. My tool makes it easier for my client to locate and verify UPC codes for nutrition queries.

FullStack Developer, Open Source founder

I am the creator of a full-stack application called My Beer Journal. This is a MERN stack application using the mongoose framework for quick and clean syntactic CRUD operations. I am in the process of building out a front end with ReactJs. This experience collaborating and working with professional developers has taught me so much about being a team player in software engineering and prepared me for corporate environments.

Backend developer, Freelance/ Open source

My client relies on a somewhat fragile api resource for their website. My web scraper serves as a backup resource for the top 100 runescape items. I ensure that the correct item data gets scraped efficiently and stored. I used cheerio and Node. Js to make this useful and efficient script.

Electrician/ Data Center Installation Tech, Miller electric (DC Blox partnered)

Installed and worked with nearly every piece of electrical and data equipment for a tier 3 DC Blox data center. Installed everything from Bus ducts for servers, and cabinets containing low voltage wired servers. Contributed to software stress testing and computational functions in servers. In a matter of 7 months we went from dirt, to a fully functional data center that serves fortune 500 clients using cloud storage on the east coast.

Sep 2022 – Oct 2022

Dec 2022 – present Charlotte, United States

Aug 2022 – Aug 2022

Jun 2021 – Dec 2021 Greenville



UPC API Search App for Nutrition ∅

Sep 2022 - Oct 2022

The application accepts upc codes to search from an api of over 650k food products. The app displays total calorie and fat content of the products. Technologies include Node.js ,React.js ,Express.js ,CORS ,dotenv, body-parser, and axios. Separate backend and Client.

Top100 Runescape Scraper ⊗

Web scraper built with cheerio, and axios. Scrapes the top 100 items and Trade count totals for items, then writes them to a singular json file. I gained the skill of asynchronous functions and object/array indexing for each item.

My Beer Journal ∂ Dec 2022 – present

Ever have a nice drink somewhere and want to remember it forever? My Beer Journal is a personal project I have started that will do that and more. Store information such as brand, flavor profile, and alcohol content. Useful for craft brewers, restaurant's and the casual drink connoisseur.

EDUCATION

United States Marine Corps

Served as an infantry squad leader in my platoon of Marines. Involved high stress decision making, extensive mental training, critical thinking as well as planning to ensure the survival and care of my squad. Notable medals include National Defense Medal, Global War on Terrorism Medal, and Good Conduct Medal.

Winthrop University

Completed Winthrop University Data Structures and Algorithms course, Web development, Web design, and mathematics including Discrete Math.

Gaston College

Completed courses in information technology, and intro to programming with C++

Aug 2022